MOHAMAD ALAMUDDIN

Arad – Bahrain · 0097334047233 moalamuddin89@gmail.com · linkedin.com/in/moalamuddin/

I'm a 7 years experienced Software Engineer. I have experience in designing and integrating enterprise applications. I worked in finance and payment applications. And in government workflows automation.

EXPERIENCE

JUNE 2015 - PRESENT

SOFTWARE SYSTEM ANALYST, INFORMATION & EGOV AUTHORITY – BAHRAIN

- **2018,2019**: Benayat.bh: Building Permits for the Kingdom of Bahrain. It manages issuing building permits and monitoring the building process.
 - Participate in meetings with the business stakeholders.
 - Discuss the technology stack and application architecture with our team members.
 - Responsible for integration with other organizations & third party teams.
 - System design and implementation of our Payment framework.
 - Train the new team members to get involved in the project quickly.
 - Live production support.
 - Technologies: Java Spring Hibernate Angular NodeJS Camunda BPMN2 –
 GIT maven Webservices Message driven integration–microservices –
 PostgreSQL
 - AWS (Cognito IAM S3 EC2 Cloud Front Amplify Lambda DynamoDB SNS SQS CFT Parameter Store).
- **2016,2017:** <u>Tasareeh:</u> An internal government system that organize workflows between Bahrain government entities.
 - This project is a portal consists of 15 separate projects. I designed and prepared the common services shared between the 15 projects. We created them as microservices.
 - Involved in technology stack and application architecture discussion with our team members.
 - Code review and code optimization.
 - Train the new team members to get involved in the project quickly.
 - Production support.
 - Technologies: Java Spring Angular Hibernate Camunda BPMN2 SVN maven – Webservices – microservices – PostgreSQL
- 2015,2016: CRMS: Content management System for Bahrain Civil Service Bureau.
 - When I joined this project it was already on production.
 - Solved data inconsistency issues.
 - Implemented dashboard backend.
 - Implemented new features requested by client.
 - Technologies: Java Spring Camunda Hibernate

MAY 2013 - MAY 2015

JAVA DEVELOPER, FAWRY INTEGRATED SYSTEMS - EGYPT

- I worked in integrating Fawry Payment Gateway with the third parties (27 integration projects in two years).
 - Integration with mobile service providers for recharge services.
 - Vodafone
 - Mobinil
 - Etisalat
 - Integration with Banks.
 - National Bank of Egypt NBE.
 - Commercial International Bank CIB.
 - Banque Misr.
 - Banque Du Caire.
 - Credit Agricole Bank.
 - Alexandria Bank.
 - HSBC.
 - Project for United Nations' "Save The Children" program.
 - Integration with Point Of Sale (POS).
 - Integration with Master Card (MIGS).
 - Integration with Egyptian Post.
 - Integration with Traffic Directorate.
 - Participated in "Super Fawry" project for paying tickets and subscription fees.
 - Implementation of four mobile wallets:
 - Vodafone wallet.
 - Mobinil wallet.
 - Etisalat wallet.
 - National Bank of Egypt wallet.
 - Technologies:
 - Java (EJBs, Hibernate)
 - SOAP, XML Parsing & Binding
 - ISO 8583
 - Oracle DB

APRIL 2012 - MAY 2013

COMPUTERS SPECIALIST, EGYPTIAN ARMED FORCES

- I was a computer specialist during my military service at The Egyptian Armed Forces. My job included IT Help Desk tasks and software development tasks:
 - Implement officers attendance system.
 - Add features and Fix bugs in SMS sending system.
 - Add features and Fix bugs in Bills & accounting system.
 - Diagnose and fix hardware and software issues in computers.
 - Network administration.
 - 24/7 IT Help desk support for officers.
 - Preparing computers and networks for conferences and meeting rooms.

JULY 2011 - APRIL 2012

JAVA DEVELOPER, NOURAIN MEDIA GROUP

- Implement backend APIs for mobile applications and websites.
- R&D in websites crawlers.

FREELANCE PROJECTS:

- Medical services Search engine. (search for doctors, hospitals and pharmacies)
- KPI monitoring system
- Mobile application for tailor shops.
- Political publication Facebook app.

SKILLS

- Java
 - EJP
 - JSP & Servlates
 - JPA, Hibernate
 - QDSL
 - Junit
- Spring
 - Spring boot
 - Spring Security
 - Spring MVC
 - Spring Thymeleaf
- JavaScript
- NodeJs
- TypeScript
 - Angular
 - PrimeNG
 - Ionic
- BPMN2
 - Camunda
 - Activiti
- Application Servers
 - IBM websphere
 - Apache Tomcat
- Integration
 - SOAP
 - REST
 - GraphQL
 - Messaging Queues
 - Oracle DB Link
 - JSON
 - XML

- Databases
 - PostgreSQL
 - Oracle
 - IBM DB2
 - MySQL
 - NoSQL databases
- AWS
 - Lambda
 - Cognito
 - IAM
 - S3
 - EC2
 - CloudFront
 - CloudWatch
 - CodeCommit
 - CodePipeline
 - DynamoDB
 - SimpleNotificationService
 - SimpleQueueService
 - CloudFormationTemplate
 - Amplify
- Google Firestore
 - Authentication
 - Realtime Database
 - Cloud Firestore
 - Cloud Functions
- Tools
 - GIT & SVN
 - Maven
 - Eclipse, Visual Studio Code
 - Jira, Trello, Microsoft Teams

EDUCATION

NOVEMBER 2011

BACHELOR OF COMPUTERS & SYSTEMS ENGINEERING, AIN SHAMS UNIVERSITY

Grade: Good 65%

Graduation Project: domain specific programming language.

Graduation Project Grade: Excellent

CERTIFICATES & AWARDS

• Oracle Certified Java Programmer – 2013 (OCJP)

- Best eGovernment Integrated Services Award Bahrain 2019 (Benayat System)
- Excellence in GIS Implementation (EGI) Award GISWORX Dubai 2017 (Tasareeh System)
- Competition of Robot Design (3rd place of 48 teams) Egypt 2009

Mohamad Alamuddin

• Muharraq, Muharraq Governorate, Bahrain

Contact Information

- 7hu-qfs-t7l@mail.dice.com (Preferred)
- 9733404723 (Preferred)

Work History

Total Work Experience: 8 years

 Senior Software Engineer | Technologies: Java - Spring - Camunda - Hibernate -AWS - Angular

Jun 01, 2015 - No End Date

• Java Developer | Fawry Integrated Systems

May 01, 2013 - May 01, 2015 | Egypt

• Computers Specialist | Egyptian Armed Fources

Apr 01, 2012 - May 01, 2013

• java developer | Nourain Media Group

Jul 01, 2011 - Apr 01, 2012

Education

• BA / BSc / BEng, No Dates Provided | Ain Shams University

Skills

- java | 9yrs | 2020
- eclipse | 8yrs | 2020

- integration | 8yrs | 2020
- j2ee | 8yrs | 2020
- software development | 8yrs | 2020
- web development | 8yrs | 2020
- web services | 8yrs | 2020
- apache tomcat | 6yrs | 2020
- hibernate | 6yrs | 2020
- html | 6yrs | 2020
- spring | 6yrs | 2020
- restful | 6yrs | 2020
- software | 6yrs | 2020
- business process management | 5yrs | 2020
- javascript | 5yrs | 2020
- postgresql | 5yrs | 2020
- production support | 5yrs | 2020
- sql | 5yrs | 2020
- systems analysis | 5yrs | 2020
- workflow | 5yrs | 2020
- amazon dynamodb | 5yrs | 2020
- amazon s3 | 5yrs | 2020
- **bpmn2** | 5yrs | 2020
- camunda | 5yrs | 2020
- cloud | 5yrs | 2020
- code optimization | 5yrs | 2020
- software architecture | 5yrs | 2020
- systems design | 5yrs | 2020
- agile | 4yrs | 2020
- bpmn | 4yrs | 2020
- code review | 4yrs | 2020
- angular | 4yrs | 2020
- nosql | 3yrs | 2020
- amazon web services | 2yrs | 2020
- business analysis | 2yrs | 2020
- git | 2yrs | 2020
- svn | 4yrs | 2018
- architecture
- design
- optimization
- s3

Work Preferences

- Likely to Switch: Most Likely
- Willing to Relocate: Yes

- Work Authorization:
 - o US
- Work Documents:
 - o Need H1
- Security Clearance: No
- Third Party: No
- Employment Type:
 - o Contract W2
 - o Contract to Hire Independent
 - o Full-time
 - o Contract to Hire W2
 - o Contract Independent

Profile Sources

- Linkedin: http://www.linkedin.com/in/moalamuddin
- Dice:

https://www.dice.com/employer/talent/profile/c71c7f548c7991426656d37b509ad99626e 0a205